我が社も朽ちたものだ
かつて戦乱の世に溢れた数多の卑しき願い
ここに刻まれたその残滓ももはや忘れられ
How my shrine has declined.
参るものもない
The world was once filled with
strife and countless vile wishes.
蠃蚌
なれど　まだ我は生きてここにいる
But their etchings here are long forgotten, and prayers are made here no more.
われ等は禍津神
生まれ這い上がるも　死に堕ちるも
Rabou...
Yet here I am, alive.
同じ場所
We are gods of calamity.
そうであろう　夜ト神
Where we rise is also where we fall.
Isn't that so...
god named Yato?
ばっ
お前何ついてきてんだよ　ひより
こ こ 　ここどこですか
Huh?
私尻尾生えてる
What?!
Hiyori, you idiot!
Why'd you come with us?!
何これ
お前
よくぞ来た
Huh?
Wh-Where are we?
I have a tail?!
蠃蚌
Huh? No way!
What's going on?!
Oh, boy.
招いてもいない客が一人
I'm glad you could make it.
あなた　本当に目障りな子ね
ひより　お前はこの場から離れてろ
Rabou...
Looks like you've brought
along an uninvited guest.
今一度
You really are an eyesore,
do you know that?
参る
雪器
Hiyori!
Huh?
零器
You need to get away from here!
Once again...
Have at you!
Sekki!
Reiki!
弾丸込めた小銃を　僕は片手に持っている
Noragami
震えた君のいる場所へ　足を早め向かっている
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
チクタク　針はチクタクと
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
焦る心を急かしただけ
dangan kometa shoujuu wo boku wa katate ni motte iru
With a loaded rifle in one hand
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
チクタク　針はチクタクと
furueta kimi no iru basho e ashi wo hayame mukatte iru
I rush to where you stand trembling
留まる気配もなく　進んでいく
チクタク　針はチクタクと
chikutaku hari wa chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wa
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
チクタク　針はチクタクと
終わりと始まりの境目
aseru kokoro wo sekashita dake
Making my heart race even faster
終わりと始まりの境目
チクタク　針はチクタクと
chikutaku hari wa chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wa
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
チクタク　針はチクタクと
todomaru kehai mo naku susunde yuku
Going on and on endlessly
全て重なった
閉口して　僕は待っていた
chikutaku hari wa chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wa
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
owari to hajimari no sakaime
In the small gap between end and beginning
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
owari to hajimari no sakaime
閉口して　僕は待っていた
chikutaku hari wa chikutaku to
chi
ku
ta
ha
ri
wa
chi
ku
ta
to
The clock is ticking
閉口して　僕は待っていた
subete kasanatta
That's where everything will happen
ドアを蹴破る　その音を
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
閉口して　僕は待っていた
I was waiting helplessly
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
閉口して　僕は待っていた
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
usugurai heya hitorikiri
In this dark room all by myself
薄暗い部屋　一人きり
閉口して　僕は待っていた
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
閉口して　僕は待っていた
もう怖れることはないよ
doa wo keyaburu sono oto wo
For the sound of the door being kicked in
もう怖れることはないよ
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
弾丸込めた小銃を持って
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
弾丸込めた小銃を持って
usugurai heya hitorikiri
In this dark room all by myself
固く閉ざされたドアを蹴破った
Heikou shite boku wa matte ita
I was there waiting helplessly
吸い付いた銃口が跳ねて
mou osoreru koto wa nai yo
There's nothing to fear now
昨日の僕を貫いた
mou osoreru koto wa nai yo
おやすみ　その絶望を受け取って
dangan kometa shoujuu wo motte
With a loaded rifle in hand
おやすみ　その絶望を受け取って
dan
gan
ko
me
ta
sho
u
ju
wo
mo
明日への僕は歩き始めた
tte
kataku tozasareta doa wo keyabutta
I kick down the locked door
明日への僕は歩き始めた
ka
ta
ku
to
za
sa
re
ta
do
a
wo
ke
ya
bu
tta
また今夜　待ち合わせよう
suitsuita juukou ga hanete
The gun recoils
また今夜　待ち合わせよう
su
i
また今夜　待ち合わせよう
tsu
i
ta
ju
u
ko
ga
ha
ne
kinou no boku wo tsuranuita
As I pierce through my past self
ki
no
u
bo
ku
wo
tsu
ra
nu
i
ta
I accept the lingering despair
oyasumi sono zetsubou wo uketotte
ashita e no boku wa arukihajimeta
And start walking toward the future
mata kon'ya machiawaseyou
ma
ta
ko
n'
ya
ma
chi
a
wa
se
you
Let's meet again tonight
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:小然&千夜  翻译:maki&迩祢  校对:小然&叶隐  时间轴:Gissa  压制:久嘉
Chapter 12
A Scrap of a Memory
You will give back...
Hiyori's memory!
ひよりの記憶を 返してもらう
We've got him!
捉えた
Too weak!
弱い
くそ　中からじゃ破れねえ
Damn! I can't break it from the inside!
Furuhime.
零姫
The god named Yato
has not yet returned.
夜ト神は今だ帰らぬままだ
Hiyori?!
ひより
いてててて
Ow.
A-Are you all right?!
大丈夫ですか
Yeah.
But what are you still doing here?!
って　何でまだいるんだよ
I told you to get out of here!
逃げろって言っただろ
Still... Thanks.
まあ　助かった
No problem.
はい
What is that look?
何だ　あの目は
あの凍て緩んだ顔は
What is that lax expression?
Where is he?!
どこだ
Who?!
The god of calamity I know!
われの知る禍津神は
Where is Yato,
the god of calamity?!
禍津神夜トは　どこだ
醜気を孕んだ美しい瞳
With those beautiful eyes of depravity...
Where is that god named Yato?
あの夜ト神はどこだ
I wish to cross swords with
that god of calamity!
われが刀を交えたいのは　あの禍津神だ
Shut up!
うるせえ
I see.
そうか
It's still not enough.
まだ足りぬのだな
What are you talking about?!
何言ってやがる
What are you—
てめぇ
Sekki!
雪器
Say, Rabou...
ねぇ　蠃蚌
あんなに大きな時化が
What an enormous Storm!
This doesn't bode well.
これは荒れるぞ
There's simply no end to the Phantoms!
あやかしどもが一向に治まらぬ
Kazuma!
カズマ
Yes?
はい
What did Kofuku-dono tell you?
小福殿から　何を聞いた
I doubt a Vent is causing
this particular Storm.
この時化は　風穴のせいではないな
これは
This is most likely the product of a tempestuous god of calamity.
恐らく　荒ぶる禍津神が生み出したもの
禍津神
A god of calamity?!
雪音
Yukine!
What are we gonna do, Yato?!
夜ト　どうすんだよ
お前はひよりを連れて　こっから離れろ
You're going to take Hiyori
and get away from here.
Huh?
I'm the one Rabou wants.
元々蠃蚌の狙いは俺だ
I'll keep him distracted.
Take that chance to escape.
俺があいつの気を引くから
その隙をつけ
But what about you?!
夜トはどうすんだよ
俺がいなきゃ　丸腰じゃねえか
Without me, you'll be completely unarmed!
Shut up! I'll figure something out!
うるせえ　何とかする
What's that?!
あれは
That ball contains Hiyori's memories.
ひよりの記憶を閉じ込めてる珠だ
Huh?!
あら　残念
What a shame.
How fleeting these things can be.
儚い物ね
ひより
Hiyori!
Hiyori... Hiyori!
ひより　ひより
Hiyori!
ひより
What do we do, Yato?!
夜ト　どうしよう　夜ト
Hiyori isn't waking up!
ひよりが目を開けない
捨ておけ　夜ト神
Forget about her, Yato.
She is but a voiceless,
mindless vessel now.
それはもう　声も発さぬ心も持たぬ器
Nothing more than a heap of flesh.
ただの肉塊だ
蠃蚌
Rabou...
Do you detest me?
われが憎いか
それで良い
Good.
Loathe me, O fierce deity.
荒御魂よ　吾を憎め
Accept and awaken to
your maelstrom of hate...
その渦に抗われず　目覚めよ
god of calamity, Yato!
禍津神夜ト
黙れ
Be quiet.
雪器
Sekki!
そうだ　その目だ
Yes... Those are the eyes.
Come!
来い
You come to me.
お前が来い
I'll hack that smirk off your face.
そのニヤケ面 切り刻んでやるよ
Yato?
夜ト
懐かしい
This brings back memories.
われ等が生きていた頃の空と同じだ
Right now, the sky is the same
as when we truly lived.
We are gods of calamity.
われ等は禍津神
忌われし願いに応え
Fierce deities that grant heinous wishes
此岸を血に染め上げる
and bathe the Near Shore in blood.
荒御魂
蠃蚌
Rabou...
これだ
This is it.
The moment I've been waiting for.
この時を待っていた
今こそ我が願い 叶う時
The moment my wish is finally granted!
My name is Rabou.
我が名は蠃蚌
Bearing a posthumous name,
I don this mask.
諱を握りて面に留めん
I hereby make myself a spirit vessel!
この身をもってよりしろとす
You who bear names that now
assemble cannot defy my orders!
集い来りしつらづらなる名々
我が命に逆らうことあたわず
Submit to and obey the mask!
ひとおもてのもと伏せしたがわせん
Gather, depravity!
集え　醜気
時化を飲み込んでる
He's... absorbing the Storm?!
Fool.
馬鹿が
Have you gone mad?
焼きにも回ったか
Merging with Phantoms like this...
あやかしと同化しやがった
Nay. I did it in order to
fight you, god named Yato.
否
夜ト神　本来の貴様と
存分に斬り合うためだ
To fight to the death!
Yato! Hey, Yato!
夜ト
おい 夜ト
Noragami
No
ra
ga
No
ra
ga
No
ra
ga
No
ra
ga
No
ra
ga
mi
No
ra
ga
mi
No
ra
ga
mi
No
ra
ga
mi
ra
ga
mi
No
ra
ga
mi
ra
ga
mi
ra
ga
mi
ra
What's happening to me?
ga
mi
どうしたんだろ 私
ga
mi
ra
ga
No
ra
Me? Who am I?
私
I don't know.
分からない
I don't know anything.
なにも分からない
なに この香り
What is that smell?
Yato! You okay?!
夜ト 大丈夫か
Yato!
夜ト
Rabou's coming!
蠃蚌が来る
Yato! Yato!
夜ト　夜ト
夜ト
Yato!
It smells nice.
いい香り
I've smelled it somewhere before.
どこかで嗅いだことがある
I...
私の
love this smell.
好きな香り
Stop... crying...
もう　泣かないで
Yato.
夜ト
Hi... Hiyori...
ひ　ひより
Hiyori!
ひより
Huh?
Hiyori! Hiyori! Hiyori!
ひより
Hiyori!
Wh-Wha...
ななななん
ジャングル　ソバット
Jungle...
Savate!
She broke free of my
spell all by herself?!
私の術を自ら解いた
Did she unlock her memories?
記憶の蓋が外れるなんて
How did she...
あの子
That's so indecent!
破廉恥
What the heck are you thinking, Yato?!
何してるんですか　夜ト
Hiyori...
ひより
You just... called me Yato.
お前今夜トって
Huh?
H-Hiyori's memory...
ひよりの記憶が戻った
is back!
Huh?
あれ　私なんで
Why am I...
ひより
Hiyori!
Why?
なぜだ
Why will you not return
to your old self?
なぜ昔のお前に戻らん
We are gods of calamity!
我らはまがつかみ
We grant depraved wishes and
live off of human greed and hate—
忌まわれし願いを受け
人の欲望と憎しみを糧に
知るか
Like I care!
Quit bringing up the past!
None of that matters anymore!
飯の種にもならねえ昔話ばっか語ってんじゃねえ
Let Hiyori go!
ひよりを離せ
So it's you.
貴様か
You are to blame!
貴様のせいか
Lowly half-Phantom...
半妖ごときが
You will serve as a
sacrifice for my power!
我が力の贄としてくれる
Sekki!
雪器
Let's take him out, Yukine!
斬るぞ　雪音
Huh?!
But from this distance,
we'll get Hiyori—
でもここからじゃひよりも
It's just like a Borderline.
境界と同じだ
Rabou's absorbed a Storm and combined with Phantoms.
蠃蚌は今 時化を取り込んであやかしと同化してやがる
Draw the line between
who lives and who dies!
どこまで斬るか
どれを生かすか
線引きしろ
M-Me?!
お　おれか
It's up to you, Yukine!
頼んだぜ雪音
We can do this!
俺たちなら　できる
Thou who dares desecrate
this land of the rising sun!
豊葦原の中津国
荒び足らせぬ「彼」のものよ
With my advent, I, the Yato god...
我夜ト神来たり降り
lay waste with Sekki...
雪器を以って砕きふせ
and expel thy vast defilement!
種々の障り穢れを打ち払わん
斬
Rend!
Yato!
夜ト
Hiyori!
ひより
You okay?!
大丈夫か
帰ろう
Let's go home!
早く
Let's hurry and go home...
早く帰ろう
夜ト
Yato!
Yato...
夜ト
Your wish...
その願い
Yato...
夜ト
has been heard loud and clear!
確かに聞き届けた
Yato!
夜ト神
Yato... god...
顔が
His face!
Just as I thought.
やっぱりな
You used a curse to
forcibly retain your body.
呪詛を使って無理やりその身を保っていたか
Why?
なぜだ
However many wishes we grant...
いくら願いを叶えようとも
people will always fear, loathe,
人はまがつかみを恐れ　忌み嫌い
and forget gods of calamity.
忘れ去る
For better or worse,
people's emotions are always fickle.
良きも悪しきも
人の思いはうつろいやすい
That is the way of things.
それは理
It is our fate to be
slain though abandon.
忘却に殺されるが我らの運命
But when I awoke after
slumbering for 500 years,
だが　五百年の眠りを経て目覚めた時
I yearned to be eliminated.
感じたのだ
Not by just anyone,
われを知らぬ者より
but by you, one who
knew and understood me.
われを知るお前に終わらせて欲しいと
迷惑な話だな
What a nuisance.
先に逝くぞ　夜ト神
I'll be leaving first,
god named Yato.
God who shares the
same fate as mine...
われと同じ運命を持つ神よ
I'm not like you.
俺とお前とは違う
A god...
神が一人
...has ceased to exist.
消えたか
Aw. Well, that was a failure.
あ～　失敗しちゃった
帰って父様にお話しなきゃ
I'd better go home and speak with Father.
So you really remember?
You remember me and Yato?
本当に思い出した
俺のことも夜トのことも
Yep!
But I have to ask, how did you
suddenly get your memory back?
でもさ
どうして急に記憶が戻ったんだろ
Huh?
It was because of Yato's...
それは夜トの
smell.
にお
Hmm? What?
ん？ どうしたの
Oh...
It's nothing! Nothing at all!
なんでもない　なんでもない
Yeah, I wonder why!
I really have no idea!
どうしてだろ 覚えてないな
Yato?
夜ト
ひより
Hiyori.
What's with that serious look?
何　改まって
It's...
お前は
It's best if you cut all ties with us.
お前は俺たちと縁を斬ったほうがいい
You'll live a much happier life that way.
そのほうが幸せに暮らしていける
So...
だから
ちょっ　おい夜ト
Hold on, Yato!
I refuse.
お断りします
I have no desire to cut my ties with you!
私　夜トたちとの縁を斬りたくありません
Wow!
You really said that, Hiyorin?!
ひよりんそんなこと言ったんだ
Whoa!
But how come?!
でもなんで
どうせよくわかんねえ意地でも張ってんだろ
She's just being hard-headed
for no good reason.
I'm not!
違います
私　これからもずっと夜トたちと一緒にいたいんです
I want to stay with you!
I want to be with you forever!
And yet you tell me to
cut all ties with you?
なのにいきなり縁を斬るだなんて
Gosh! Way to go, Hiyorin!
ひよりんやっる
Huh?
Booze!
酒だ
This calls for a celebration!
祝い酒だ
U-Um...
あ　あの
一緒にいたいってのは変な意味じゃなくて
When I said, "be with you forever," I didn't mean it like that!
I'll grant that wish...
その願い 聞いてやるから
for 5 yen!
五円
Your wish...
お前の願い
has been heard loud and clear!
確かに聞き届けた
Iki Hiyori...
壱岐ひより
あなたにご縁があらんことを
May our fates intertwine!
Whatever happens I will surely call out your name
ki
mi
no
na
ma
e
na
ni
ga
a
tte
mo
ka
na
ra
zu
yo
bu
ka
ra
君の名前 何があっても
必ず呼ぶから
Your heart is all jagged
ki
mi
wa
gi
za
ha
a
to
no
mo
chi
nu
shi
君はぎざぎざハートの持ち主
So you hurt anything you touch
fu
re
ru
mo
no
wa
na
n
de
mo
ki
zu
tsu
ke
ru
触れるものは何でも傷つけ
Those eyes that frown at everything
se
ka
i
no
su
be
te
wo
ni
ra
mi
tsu
ke
te
世界のすべてを睨み付けて
その目は言うんだ
They are saying "I'm here! See me!"
so
no
me
wa
i
un
da
bo
ku
wa
ko
ni
iru
「僕はここにいる」
Someone was laughing at you
da
re
ka
ga
wa
ra
tte
ta
誰かが笑ってた
だから引いたんだ その境界線
So you put that barrier around you
da
ka
ra
hi
i
tan
da
so
no
kyo
u
ka
i
sen
But I'll reach in there with my hand
so
re
na
ra
wa
ta
shi
ga
so
no
te
wo
hi
ku
それなら
私はその手を引く
さぁ
And bring you out
tsu
re
te
ku
ka
ra
連れてくから
If you don't have words, just grasp my hand
i
e
na
i
ra
ko
no
te
wo
tsu
yo
ku
ni
gi
tte
言えないなら
この手を強く握って
And don't let go
ha
na
sa
i
de
離さないで
君はもう一人じゃないんだって
I want you to know that you
ki
mi
wa
mo
u
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
n
da
tte
知ってほしいんだよ
Are not alone any more
shi
tte
ho
shi
in
da
yo